verticalmeasures.com 2009-06-16

# Privacy Policy | Vertical Measures

Introduction 

Vertical Measures LLC respects each individual’s right to personal privacy. We will collect and use information through our Web site only in the ways disclosed in this statement. This statement applies solely to information collected at Vertical Measures LLC’s Web site. 

Information Collection 

Vertical Measures LLC collects information through our Web site at several points. We collect the following information about primary visitors: Common web analytics data collected via JavaScript and Cookies, as well as information through our information request forms. 

Vertical Measures does not actively market to children, and we never knowingly ask a person under 18 to divulge personal information. 

We collect demographic data in order to better understand our overall market and their browsing habits through our website. 

We collect this information through information request forms, clickstream tracking and automatic logging files. The information is collected involuntarily. To receive our products and services, your email address and telephone number is mandatory in order to most effectively explain our services in relation to your needs. Other information we request is optional where indicated. 

We do employ cookies. A cookie is a small text file that our Web server places on a user’s computer hard drive to be a unique identifier. Cookies enable Vertical Measures LLC to track usage patterns and deliver customized content to users. Our cookies do have an expiration date. Our cookies do not collect personally identifiable information. 

Information Usage.

The information collected by Vertical Measures LLC will be used for clickstream reporting and/or contacting you in order to discuss our services, at your request. Users who provide information will receive an email or telephone call to explain our services and how they may benefit your organization. 

The information we collect may be used to create customer profiles based on browsing or purchasing history. We may supplement information collected at our Web site with data from other sources. 

We offer links to other Web sites. Please note: When you click on links to other Web sites, we encourage you to read their privacy policies. Their standards may differ from ours. 

Our policy on information collection or uses changes periodically, we advise you to check our privacy policy for updates. 

Access to Information

Users may access their own personal information and contact us about inaccuracies they may find by using the "contact" form on our site. Users may delete their personal information from our database by using the "contact" form on our site. 

Problem Resolution 

If problems arise, users may contact Vertical Measures LLC by calling 602-476-1889 or using the "contact" form on this site. We are committed to resolving disputes within 2-3 business days. 

Data Storage and Security

Vertical Measures LLC protects user information through security measures commonly-accepted as adequate.

## SEO Videos

Our short [SEO Videos](http://www.verticalmeasures.com/resources/seo-tutorial-video/) discuss a number of onsite SEO tips and techniques to improve your search engine ranking. These SEO videos offer a hands-on approach, so that immediately following the video, you can look at your website and determine if it is properly optimized. If not, making the fix may require html coding knowledge or the assistance of your webmaster.
